Guide to the Franco Modigliani papers, 1936-2005 and undated, bulk 1970s-2003 RL.00905
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Engagements Series, 1963-2003 and undated, 16 boxes
  - Commitments Subseries, 1963-2003 and undated
    - 1997 (Box E14)
      - Jan.-Dec., Commitments (Box E14)
      - Mar. 18-26, Rotterdam, London, LA (Box E14)
      - May 21, EMC2 Computer Systems (Box E14)
      - May, Salvatore Randi (Box E14)
      - June, Europe (Box E14)
      - Sept. 23, IAFE conference Boston (Box E14)
      - Oct. 2, Bilbao (Box E14)
      - Oct. 8, 5th International Culture Economy meeting Cordoba (Box E14)
      - Oct. 12, L'Aquila (MIT Italy) (Box E14)
      - Oct. 14, London (Box E14)
      - Oct. 27, NACO Washington (Box E14)
      - Oct., Colorado College (Box E14)
      - 1997 Refusals (Box E14)
    - 1998
      - Jan. 15, Luxembourg (Box E14)
      - Jan.-Dec., Commitments (Box E14)
      - Feb., London (Box E14)
      - Mar.-Nov., Bancari (Box E14)
      - Apr. 27-May 1, Frankfurt (Box E14)
      - Spring, Europe (Box E14)
      - Oct. 3, Confindustria Italy (Box E14)
      - Oct. 25, Gorbachev Foundation conference (Box E14)
      - 1998 Refusals (Box E14)
    - 1999
      - Jan.-Dec., Commitments (Box E14)
      - Sept. 3-5, Villa d'Este (Box E14)
      - 1999 Refusals (Box E14)
    - 2000
      - Jan.-Dec., Commitments (Box E14)
      - 2000 Refusals (Box E14)
    - 2001
      - Jan.-Dec., Commitments (Box E14)
      - Dec. 1, Nobel centennial (Box E14)
    - 2002
      - July-Nov., Commitments (Box E14)
    - 2003
      - Feb.-July, Commitments (Box E14)
      - Oct. 3, Pensmart Germany (Box E14)
  - Calendars Subseries, 1971-2003
    - 1971-1986, 6 folders (Box E15)
    - Circa 1985-1986, Personal schedules (Box E15)
    - 1987-1991 (Box E15)
    - 1988 and undated, Daily schedules and related memorandums (Box E15)
    - Apr.-May 1989; Sept., Nov.-Dec. 1989, Desk calendars (Box E15)
    - 1991, Appointment book (Box E15)
    - 1992, Administrator appointment book (Box E15)
    - 1992-1994, Academic planner, monthly appointment book (Box E16)
    - 1996, Modigliani's assistant's monthly planner (Box E16)
    - 1996-1997, Monthly planner (Box E16)
    - 1998-2001, Weekly appointments, 2 folders (Box E16)
    - 2002-2003, Monthly appointments (Box E16)
- Printed Materials Series, 1936-2005 and undated, bulk 1950s-2003, 14 boxes
  Organized into three subseries: Articles (largest in the series), Other Printed Materials, and Clippings. Subseries are further described below.
  - Articles Subseries, 1936-2003 and undated, 11 boxes
    Houses a nearly complete set of reprints of Modigliani's writings throughout his career. Many of his early articles published in Italy during the 1930s are included. Modigliani's 1944 thesis, along with research files related to published writings, can be found in the Writings and Speeches Series. As Modigliani's output was chiefly in article form rather than in book-length works, this subseries represents a significant body of his published research, analysis, and commentary. Organized in rough alphabetical order as received originally. For a complete bibliography of Modigliani's published articles and working papers by title, consult the Modigliani collection information folders in the research room at the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library.
    - Ac-Alc, 1958-1997 (Box PM1)
    - Alc, 1967 (Box PM1)
    - All, 2000 (Box PM1)
    - Alt, 1975-2000, 2 folders (Box PM1)
    - An-Be, 1938-1994 (Box PM1)
    - Be-Bu, 1988-2003 (Box PM1)
    - Bu-Ca, 1957-1997 (Box PM1)
    - Ce-Ch, 1957-2003 (Box PM1)
    - Comm-Concer, 1970-2002 and undated (Box PM2)
    - Consu-Conv, 1937-1984 (Box PM2)
    - Cost-Coupon, 1958-1980 (Box PM2)
    - Cr, 1976-1995 (Box PM2)
    - Cr, 1960-1994 (Box PM2)
    - Cu-De, 1936-1983 (Box PM2)
    - Dep-Der, 1956-1992 (Box PM2)
    - Des, 1994 (Box PM2)
    - Det, 1956-1988 (Box PM2)
    - Dis, 1949-1999, folders 1-2 of 3 (Box PM2)
    - Dis, 1949-1999, folder 3 of 3 (Box PM3)
    - Dis-Div, 1938-1990 (Box PM3)
    - Dy-Ec, 1955-1987 (Box PM3)
    - Ec, 1987-1998 (Box PM3)
    - Ef-El, 1952-1988 (Box PM3)
    - Em, 1958-1992 (Box PM3)
    - En-Es, 1966-1996 (Box PM3)
    - Ex-Eu, 1976-1998 (Box PM3)
    - Eur, 1995 (Box PM3)
    - Fi-Fl, 1949-1987 (Box PM4)
    - Fl-Go, 1958-2001 (Box PM4)
    - Go-Hi, 1959-1989 (Box PM4)
    - Ho-Im, 1964-2003 (Box PM4)
    - Imp, 1978 (Box PM4)
    - Im-In, 1967-1990 (Box PM4)
    - Inf, 1967-1990, 1-2 of 5 folders (Box PM4)
    - Inf, 1967-1990, folders 3-5 of 5 (Box PM5)
    - Inf-Int, 1966-1986 (Box PM5)
    - Int, 1972-1973 (Box PM5)
    - Int-Ke, 1960-2003 (Box PM5)
    - Le-Li, 1992-1998 (Box PM5)
    - Lif, 1963-1966, 2 folders (Box PM5)
    - Lif-Lin, 1956-1975 (Box PM6)
    - Lin-Liq, 1944-1955 (Box PM6)
    - Liq, 1944-1968 (Box PM6)
    - Liq-Lo, 1949-1993 (Box PM6)
    - Ma-Me, 1952-1987 (Box PM6)
    - Me-Mi, 1962-2003 (Box PM6)
    - Mm-Mo, 1966-1988 (Box PM6)
    - Mon, 1968-1981, folder 1 of 3 (Box PM6)
    - Mon, 1968-1981, folders 2-3 of 3 (Box PM7)
    - Mo-Ne, 1949-1987 (Box PM7)
    - New, 1969 (Box PM7)
    - Ne-No, 1977-1995, folder 1 of 2 (Box PM7)
    - No, 1977-1981, folder 2 of 2 (Box PM7)
    - Nu-Op, 1979-2001 (Box PM7)
    - Opt, 1978 (Box PM7)
    - Or-Pe, 1947-2001 (Box PM7)
    - Pe-Po, 1960-1992 (Box PM8)
    - Pol, 1977-1978 (Box PM8)
    - Pol-Pr, 1937-1985 (Box PM8)
    - Pri, 1957-2003 (Box PM8)
    - Pri-Pro, 1955-1957 (Box PM8)
    - Pro, 1955-2003 (Box PM8)
    - Pr-Pu, 1966-1997 (Box PM8)
    - Pu-Re, 1953-1988 (Box PM8)
    - Rea, 1988 (Box PM9)
    - Rec, 1990 (Box PM9)
    - Rec-Red, 1986-1990 (Box PM9)
    - Red-Rep, 1959-1997 (Box PM9)
    - Rep-Res, 1959-1987 (Box PM9)
    - Ret-Ri, 1984-2003 (Box PM9)
    - Ro-Ru, 1988-1992 (Box PM9)
    - Ru-Sa, 1990-1992 (Box PM9)
    - Sc-Sh, 1959-2003 (Box PM9)
    - Si, 1958-1997 (Box PM10)
    - Si-So, 1975-1998, folder 1 of 2 (Box PM10)
    - Soc, 1998, folder 2 of 2 (Box PM10)
    - Som, 1964-1976, 2 folders (Box PM10)
    - Som-Sou, 1960-1975 (Box PM10)
    - St, 1966-1979 (Box PM10)
    - St-Su, 1966-1980 (Box PM10)
    - Su, 1966 (Box PM11)
    - Su-Th, 1957-1999 (Box PM11)
    - Th-Tr, 1973-1980 (Box PM11)
    - Tr, 1966-1973 (Box PM11)
    - Tw-U.S., 1986-1998 (Box PM11)
    - U.S.-Vo, 1954-2003 (Box PM11)
    - Wh-Wo, 1981-1993 (Box PM11)
  - Books Subseries, 1962-1998, 1 box
    Four hard-bound and one soft-bound books, three of which are on economic theories; one is a textbook on the development of Western Civilization. All have marginalia either by Franco or Serena Modigliani, and one has a sheet of notes laid in.
    - The Development of Civilization: A Documentary HIsotyr of Politics, SOciety, and Thought, Vol. 1, Harry J. Carroll et al., Foresman and Co., 1961 (Box PM12)
      Textbook. Only a few underlined sections.
    - Money and Credit: Their Influence on Jobs, Prices, and Growth, report of the Commission on Money and Credit, Prentice-Hall, 1961 (Box PM12)
      With some marginal notes, chiefly in the chapter on monetary policy.
    - Value and Capital, J.R. Hicks, Oxford, 1939 (Box PM12)
      With marginal notes, chiefly in the chapter on interest, and a sheet of notes laid in, same chapter.
    - Wage Restraint: A Study of Incomes POlicies in Western Europe, Lloyd Ulman and Robert J. Flanagan, Univ. of California Press, 1971 (Box PM12)
      Marginal notes scattered throughout. Coffee cup ring on cover.
  - Clippings Subseries, 1977-2005 and undated, 1 box
    Newspaper and magazine clippings chiefly related to events in Modigliani's career, with particular emphasis on the 1985 Nobel Prize in Economics. There are also interviews with Modigliani, and news articles written by journalists reporting on Modigliani's views on Italian and U.S. economic policies and the political process. Editorials on economic and social issues written by Modigliani can be found in the Writings and Speeches Series (Non-Academic Works and Speeches and Lectures Subseries). Other interviews can also be located in the Audio and Visual Materials Series. Organized in three language groupings (English, German, and Italian) and one topical group on a conference, and chronologically within.
    - English, 1985 Oct. 15-1986 Jan. 2 and undated (Box PM13)
    - Fondi pensione per un capitalismo piú responsabile (12/1997) [press clippings on conference], 1997 Sept. (Box PM13)
    - German, 1994 and undated (Box PM13)
    - Italian, 1977-2005 and undated (Box PM13)
    - Italian financial crisis, 1995 Jan.-Feb. (Box PM13)
  - Other Printed Materials Subseries, 1962-1998, 1 box
    These are few in number and consist of published works, including some reports from Italian symposia or conferences. Of particular interest is a 1955 report by Jacques Drèze, signed by him, and a thesis from 2003 by Laura Vallicelli of the University of Pavia, exploring Modigliani's work on the Italian economy. Also includes a few MIT directories. Organized in alphabetical order by folder title.
    - Application des methodes econometriques a la gestion industrielle: politique des stocks et du planning de la production, Jacques Drèze, 1955 Nov. (79 pp.) (Box PM14)
      This soft-bound report in French, summarizing the proceedings of a seminar in June 1955 at Liege, France, was printed and distributed to the participants, chief among whom Franco Modigliani. It was slated for later publication. Includes a bibliography.
    - ATTI: Meeting per lo sviluppo, 1987-1988 (Box PM14)
    - CIRIEC, Notizie ai soci, 1962 (Box PM14)
    - La dinamica macroeconomica dell'Italia dell'ultimo decennio: i suggerimenti e le crtiche di Franco Modigliani, Laura Vallicelli, Universitá di Pavia, Italy, 2003 (221 pp.) (Box PM14)
      In Italian. Spiral-bound, with bibliography, online resources, and tables. Department of Political Science PhD thesis that explores the Italian and European economies during the 1990s, and describes Modigliani's responses to these economic trends and other economists' analyses.
    - Directories, 1979, 1987, 1988, 1991 (Box PM14)
    - Guida ai fondi comuni, 1986 Apr. 14 (Box PM14)
    - Materials regarding Encyclopaedia of Social Sciences and Fact Book from New School for Social Research, 1963, 1998 (Box PM14)
    - MIT annual report, 1985-1986 (Box PM14)
    - Symposium on budget balance, 1986 (Box PM14)
    - US-USSR conference on economic modeling, 1976 (Box PM14)
  - Clippings Subseries, 1977-2005 and undated, 1 box
    - English, 1985 Oct. 15-1986 Jan. 2 and undated (Box PM12)
    - Fondi pensione per un capitalismo piú responsabile (12/1997) [press clippings on conference], 1997 Sept. (Box PM12)
    - German, 1994 and undated (Box PM12)
    - Italian, 1977-2005 and undated (Box PM12)
    - Italian financial crisis, 1995 Jan.-Feb. (Box PM12)
- Audio and Visual Materials Series, 1963-2003 and undated, 10 boxes
  Various audio and audiovisual formats document Modigliani's career and his presence in national and international media. Organized into the following format subseries: Photographic Materials, Videocassettes, Audiocassettes, and Microfilms. Many of the items relate to manuscript or printed materials housed in other series. Audiocassettes were originally housed in the Teaching Materials Series, the Speeches and Lectures Subseries in the Writings and Speeches Series, and the Engagements Series. There is one DVD of a memorial for Modigliani, 2003, housed in the Personal Files Series.
  [Original audiovisual materials are closed to use. Use of these materials may require production of listening or viewing copies. Please contact Research Services before coming to use this collection.]
  - Photographic Materials Subseries, 1963-2000 and undated
    A variety of informal snapshots, media images, and formal portraits of Modigliani, his students, and his colleagues. Includes one color portrait of all Nobel Prize winners in economics up until 1991. A few transparencies of data are located in the Writings and Speeches Series. Arranged in chronological order.
    - 1963, Modigliani at West Point (Box VIS1)
    - 1964-1999 and undated, Unidentified (Box VIS1)
    - 1985-1988, Press (Box VIS1)
    - 1987, Modigliani (Box VIS1)
    - 1987 May, 2004, Gustavo Marturet, Leah Modigliani, and Franco Modigliani (Box VIS1)
    - 1991 Dec. 10, Nobel Laureates (Box VIS1)
    - Circa 1993-1994, undated, Modigliani at M.I.T. Italian students' party; unidentified photographs (Box VIS1)
    - 1997 June, Modigliani with President Luigi Scalfaro of Italy (Box VIS1)
    - 1998, Publicity (Box VIS1)
    - 2000 Oct. 20-21; 2004 May, Convegno I.S.E.O. c/o Univ. di Brescia, Italy; Modigliani and Tommaso Padoa-Schioppa (Box VIS1)
    - Undated, Newspaper clipping of photograph of Modigliani and Robert Solow (Box VIS1)
  - Videocassettes Subseries, 1985-2003 and undated
    Chiefly recordings of interviews in various locations. Many are in Italian, but some are in English and German. Most relate to U.S. presidential administrations and their economic policies, or Italian economic policies. One videocassette concerns the Nobel Prize, and possibly contains biographical information as well as a recording of Modigliani's acceptance speech or lecture. Arranged in chronological order. Total running time (TRT), if known, shown in parentheses.
    [Originals closed to use. Listening copies are available.]
    - Originals OR1-19 (CLOSED)
      - OR1. 1985, Nobel Prize. Format: VHS. (TRT 11:30) (Box VIS2)
      - OR2. 1987 Nov. 23, The Silent Stars. Format: VHS. (TRT 34:14) (Box VIS2)
        Interview, with questions in German, answers in English.
      - OR3. 1992, Amato Government 1992, interview on Italian TV. Format: VHS. (TRT 32:55) (Box VIS2)
        On the Amato government and the economic measures taken to prepare Italy's entry into Maastricht.
      - OR4. Circa 1992, Interview by Italian TV at MIT, in Italian. Format: VHS. (TRT 11:03) (Box VIS2)
      - OR5. 1996 Mar. 17, Interview by Bernard Osher, Amici Telenews (TRT 21:05) (Box VIS2)
      - OR6. 1997 Apr. 23, Interview, Bloomberg TV, Italy. Format: VHS. (TRT 2:50) (Box VIS2)
      - OR7. 1997 May 23, Declaration for the European Bank. Format: VHS. (TRT 13:22) (Box VIS2)
        Discusses reasons for economic differences between Northern and Southern Italy.
      - OR8-A. 1997 June 16, 50 Review, Part 1, Rome. Format: VHS. (TRT 60:00) (Box VIS2)
      - OR8-B. 1997 June 16, 50 Review, Part 1, Rome. Format: VHS. (TRT 58:00) (Box VIS2)
      - OR9. 1997 June 16, 50 Review, Part 2, Rome. Format: VHS. (TRT 1:30:15) (Box VIS2)
      - OR10. 1997 June 16, 50 Review, Part 3, with Modigliani as last speaker, Rome. Format: VHS. (TRT 1:43:41) (Box VIS2)
      - OR11. 1997, Una Buffonesca: 1997 Debate in Rome. Format: VHS. (TRT 1:23:53) (Box VIS2)
        With Innocenzo Cipolletta, Lamberto Dini, Martini.
      - OR12. 1999 Feb. 12, Chaos on Pensions. Italian TV. Format: VHS. (TRT 1:00:02) (Box VIS3)
      - OR13. 1999 Apr. 15, Interview by Paolo Peluffo, in Italian. Format: VHS. (TRT 11:52) (Box VIS3)
        About publication of Modigliani's memoirs, Adventures of an Economist.
      - OR14. 1999, Social Security, interview with Peter Diamond on Clinton administration. Format: VHS. (TRT 1:09:53) (Box VIS3)
      - OR15. 2003 June 4, Interview by Italian TV at Modigliani's home. Format: VHS. (TRT 26:12) (Box VIS3)
      - OR16. Undated, Against a change in patent law. Format: VHS. (TRT 3:05) (Box VIS3)
        Joint deposition by Modigliani, James Tobin, et al., against a proposed change in the patent law.
      - OR17. Undated, Interview in Frankfurt, in German. Format: VHS. (TRT 5:04) (Box VIS3)
      - OR18. Undated, Interview at MIT in Modigliani's office, on Reagan years, Italian TV. Format: VHS. (TRT 36:00) (Box VIS3)
      - OR19. Undated, Interview with Robert Solow, and Modigliani in a different section. Format: VHS. (TRT 42:55) (Box VIS3)
    - Videocassettes, Master Copies 1-19
      [Format: BetacamSP. Source: ORIG 1-19.]
      [Not for reference use. Use copies are available.]
      - MC 1-10 (Box VIS4)
      - MC 11-19 (Box VIS5)
    - Videocassettes, Use Copies 1-19 (Box VIS6)
      [Format: DVD. Source: ORIG 1-19.]
  - Audiocassettes Subseries, 1978, 1981, 1993 and undated
    The bulk of the audiocassettes consists of recordings from a single unidentified class taught by Modigliani at MIT in spring semester, 1978; recorded lectures from one 1981 MIT seminar on banks and industry between World War I and World War II; and one 1993 interview. Arranged in original series order, then chronologically within.
    - Original Copies 1-25 (CLOSED) (Box VIS7)
      - Writings and Speeches Series, Speeches and Lectures Subseries
        - Modigliani interview, 1993, Tape 1 of 25 (Box VIS7)
      - Teaching Materials Series
        - Economics class (unidentified), 1978 Mar. 23-May 18 and undated, Tapes 2-17 of 25 (Box VIS7)
      - Engagements Series, Commitments Subseries
        - MIT Seminar Banks and Industry in the Interwar Period, 1981, Tapes 18-25 of 25 (Box VIS7)
    - Audiocassettes, Use Copies 1-25 (Box VIS8)
  - Scrapbooks (microfilms), 1966-2004 (Box VIS9)
    Family scrapbooks containing clippings and other memorabilia related to Modigliani's career, reformatted to microfilm reels. Images are in chronological order as they appear in the scrapbooks.
    - Microfilms, Print Master Copies 1-5, 1966-2004, 5 reels (Box VIS9)
      [Not for reference use. Use copies available. Created 2004.]
    - Microfilms, Archival Master Copies 1-5, 1966-2004, 5 reels (Box VIS9a)
    - Microfilms, Use Copies 1-5, 1966-2004, 5 reels (Box VIS10)
- Electronic Formats Series, 1993-2003, 18 diskettes, 185 files
  Digital files, mostly unidentified beyond general categories, including drafts of writings, some correspondence, and data related to Modigliani's publications, teaching, and presentations. Arranged in the original order in which disks were located in the collection.
  - Copie di tutti i file (correspondence, extracts from articles), 1994-1998. Disk 001., 77 files (Box VIS10)
  - Correspondence, extracts from articles, 1998. Disk 002., 8 files (Box VIS10)
  - Rosenberg talk; Brandeis talk; chapters 1,4,6; appendices, 2003. Disk 003., 8 files (Box VIS10)
  - Chapter 5, 7, 8; Appendices, 2003. Disk 004., 3 files (Box VIS10)
  - Chapter 3, 2003. Disk 005., 2 files (Box VIS10)
  - Solution to the Social Security Crisis, 1997-1999. Disk 006., 6 files (Box VIS10)
  - Worksheets for Solution to the Social Security Crisis, 1994-2000. Disk 007., 7 files (Box VIS10)
  - The Chinese Saving Puzzle, 2004. Disk 008., 1 file (Box VIS10)
  - Modigliani-Modigliani Measure of Risk-Adjusted Performance (with Leah Modigliani), 1996. Disk 009., 1 file (Box VIS10)
  - Academic articles, 2003. Disk 010., 3 files (Box VIS10)
  - Santa Fe regressions, 2000. Disk 011., 1 file (Box VIS10)
  - Various articles, 1998-1999. Disk 012., 16 files (Box VIS10)
  - Various articles, 1998-2003. Disk 013., 20 files (Box VIS10)
  - Various non-academic articles, 1999-2002. Disk 014., 9 files (Box VIS10)
  - Capital Markets, 15.432 materials (Fall 1992), 1993-1994. Disk 015., 8 files (Box VIS10)
  - Capital Markets, 15.432 materials (Spring 1992), 1994. Disk 016., 2 files (Box VIS10)
  - China conference (1994 July 8-11), 1993. Disk 017., 12 files (Box VIS10)
  - Frankfurt interview with Franco Modigliani, translated to German, 1999. Disk 018., 1 file (Box VIS10)
- Oversize Materials, 2 boxes, 1 folder
  Contains clippings, statistical data and econometric estimations, diplomas and honorary materials, and other items. Arranged in series order, according to the original locations of the oversize materials in the main collection.
  - Correspondence Series, 1947-2003 and undated, bulk 1973-1999
    - Ando, Albert (Oversize-box OS1)
      - Massachusetts Institute of Technology - Federal Reserve Bank [MIT-FRB] Project, 1968 (Oversize-box OS1)
      - Mishkin, Frederick - Mishkin's data - simulation output, circa 1975 (Oversize-box OS1)
    - Association of Independent Colleges and Universities in Massachusetts [AICUM], 1987 (Oversize-box OS1)
    - Banca d'Italia, Distribuzioni tributarie, 1970 (Oversize-box OS1)
    - Cohn, Richard, data from Henry Townsend manuscript, undated (Oversize-box OS1)
    - Committee on Developing American Capitalism, published graphs, 1986 undated (Oversize-box OS1)
    - Economic Policy Institute, manifesto signed by 327 economists, circa 1989 (Oversize-box OS1)
    - Gasparini, Innocenzo, statistical data for monetary equilibrium, 1947 (Oversize-box OS1)
    - M General, 1990-1993 (Oversize-box OS1)
    - Modigliana, Italy, 1993 (Oversize-folder OF1)
      Poster welcoming Franco and Serena Modigliani during visit on the occasion of becoming honorary citizen of Modigliana
    - National Academy of Science, clipping of MIT faculty awarded membership, 1973 (Oversize-box OS1)
    - Nobel Prize
      - B General, clipping, Marco Pannella article, circa 1985 (Oversize-box OS1)
      - D General, clipping, Seis meses de Plan Austral, 1986 (Oversize-box OS1)
      - Letters of congratulations, music score to Columbus sent to FM, 1986 (Oversize-box OS1)
      - P General, Invitation from U.S. Treasury, Bonds Division, 1985 December (Oversize-box OS1)
    - Perotti, Enrico, newspapers and clipping, 1988, 1989 (Oversize-box OS1)
    - Petitions and protest letters - against Silvio Berlusconi, clipping, 2003 (Oversize-box OS1)
    - Pogue, Gerry, royalty agreement with FM, for D. C. Heath Co., 1973 (Oversize-box OS1)
    - Promostudio - Giovanni Vescovo, clipping on European Business School, 1991 (Oversize-box OS1)
    - Rasche, Robert, 1967-1972 - Enzler, Jeremy, Dynamic Simulation of the Demand for Demand Deposits, 1972 (Oversize-box OS1)
    - Weintraub, Sidney, 1974 - Tobin, James, There are Three Types of Inflation: We Have Two, 1974 (Oversize-box OS1)
  - Writings and Speeches Series, undated
    - Life cycle hypothesis and consumption function - Wealth - National debt - Capital coefficient - Econometric estimations, undated (Oversize-box OS1)
    - 1997 June 5, Universitá di Studi a Napoli, Incontro con Franco Modigliani (poster) (Oversize-folder OF1)
  - Teaching Materials Series, 1996
    - Topics in Finance and Economics, 1996 Spring (Oversize-box OS1)
  - Printed Materials Series, 2003 Sept.
    - Clippings--Italian, 2003 Sept. (Oversize-box OS1)
  - Personal Files Series, 1960-1997
    - 1960-1997, Diplomas and degrees, 4 folders; 34 items (Oversize-box OS2)
- Accession (2008-0067), 1985-2005, 1 boxes
  The addition (2008-0067) (50 items; 0.2 lin. ft.; 1985-2005) includes clippings, photographs, and ephemera related to Modigliani's Nobel Prize, and 1 journal issue including a memorial for Modigliani. Much of the material is in Italian. This accession has not been processed.
  - Miscellaneous materials (Box 1)
- Accession (2009-0114), 1930s-2003, 7 boxes
  The addition (2009-0114) (3140 items; 4.2 lin. ft.; 1930s-2003) includes books, articles, correspondence, videotapes, audiotapes, and newspaper clippings and photocopies. Also included are some photographs, 3 pipes, 2 diplomas, and other miscellaneous materials, such as Modigliani's curriculum vitae and appointment books. This accession has not been processed.
  - Videotapes (Box 1)
    - A Tribute to Herbert Simon, Mar. 19, 2001 (Box 1)
    - Perlasca un eroe italiano, Part I-II (Box 1)
    - Social Security 1999, Peter Diamond, Franco Modigliani (Box 1)
    - ALPI (Box 1)
    - Presentazione Volume La Lira Italiana, Bari, June 28, 1993 (Box 1)
    - Amici Telenews: Professor Franco Modigliani, San Francisco interview, Mar. 17, 1996 (Box 1)
    - RAI at MIT office: Reagan Years (Box 1)
    - Interview, Aug. 1992 (Box 1)
    - RAI, March 1999 (Box 1)
    - Swiss or German TV interview, Fall 1987 (Box 1)
    - Intervista Dott Paolo Peluffo, 1999? (Box 1)